<page>

<title>developer information</title>

<menu>
 <item><a href="http://www.nutch.org/cgi-bin/twiki/view/Main/Nutch">Wiki</a></item>
 <item><a href="http://incubator.apache.org/nutch/mailing_lists.html">Mailing Lists</a></item> 
 <item><a href="http://incubator.apache.org/nutch/version_control.html">Version Control</a></item>
 <item><a href="tutorial.html">Tutorial</a></item>
 <item><a href="i18n.html">i18n</a></item>
 <item><a href="http://www.nutch.org/release/">Download</a></item>
 <item><a href="../api/index.html">Javadoc</a></item>
 <item><a href="http://incubator.apache.org/nutch/issue_tracking.html">Bugs</a></item>
 <item><a href="policies.html">Policies</a></item>
 <item><a href="bot.html">Webmasters</a></item>
</menu>

<body>

<h3>How to Contribute</h3>

<p>Contributions are merit-based.  Other developers must see
contributions in order to evaluate them, suggest improvements, and
integrate them into the sourcebase.</p>

<p>Contributors should follow these steps:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Check the nutch developers mailing list to see if anyone is
already working on what you are interested in working on.  If so, you
might want to contact that person to see how far along the work has
come.</li>

  <li> If it looks like you are not duplicating effort, send
a small piece of mail saying you are about to do the work.  When
future people want to contribute, they will see your letter during
step (1) above.</li>

  <li> Once you've done some, submit the diffs to the nutch developers
mailing list, or attach them to a bug report.  We can all then examine
the work for quality, relevance, etc.  Details like formatting,
documentation, and coding conventions are important.</li>

  <li> We hope everyone will try to provide good feedback on your work, 
but honestly everyone's time is very limited.  Make it easy for
people to examine your work by making it:
   <ul>
    <li>high-quality;</li>
    <li>easy-to-read; and</li>
    <li>easy-to-integrate; and</li>
    <li>relevant to Nutch's stated goals.</li>
   </ul>
  </li>

  <li> If everything seems right, we'll accept it into the source 
base and it will become part of Nutch.</li>

  <li> Collect glory and good karma.  Goto step 1.</li>
</ol>

<p>Please also read the developer <a href="policies.html">policies</a>
page.</p>

<h3>Needed contributions</h3>

Nutch needs contributions in the following areas (among others).  If
you think you can help with these, or with something else, please send
a message to <a
href="mailto:dev@nutch.org">dev@nutch.org</a>.

<h4>Internationalization</h4>

<p>Nutch intends to be international.  At present, we believe that
our indexing works well for western languages.  But we need:
<ul>
<li>Translations of the basic Nutch pages (at least <tt>search.xml</tt>,
<tt>help.xml</tt> and <tt>about.xml</tt>) into other languages.</li>
<li>Testing and development work on improved Asian language support</li>
</ul>
More information about how to internationalize can be found on the <a
href="i18n.html">i18n</a> page.
</p>


<h4>Search Parameter Tuning</h4>

<p>Nutch has not yet been tuned for quality.  There are ten or twenty
knobs that we can twiddle to adjust the ranking formula.  We have
started developing software to do this tuning automatically, but the
current code just contains guesses.  With a little tuning we should be
able to get results that are competitive with those of major search
engines.</p>

<h4>Alternate Content Types</h4>

<p>Nutch currently only supports HTML content accessed by HTTP.  It
would be great to add support for PDF files, image search, etc.</p>

</body>
</page>
