<page>

<title>donate</title>

<body>

<p>Monetary donations to Nutch gratefully accepted.</p>

<p>Our current goal is to create a good-sized public demo that can
handle moderate traffic.  Even this takes a fair amount of hardware
and bandwidth.  Fortunately, the Internet Archive has donated
bandwidth, so all that we need now is hardware.  We estimate that a
two-hundred-million page demo system will require from $10,000 to
$200,000 in hardware, depending on how much query traffic we wish to
handle.</p>

<p>If you believe in the cause and think a more compelling Nutch demo
would help it, please donate.</p>

<h3>U.S. Tax Exempt Status</h3>

<p>The Nutch <a href="org.html">Organization</a> is applying for
federal tax-exempt status as a 501(c)3 corporation.  Once that
application is accepted, donations by United States residents will be
tax deductable.</p>

<h3>The Nutch Store</h3>

All profits from sales at <a href="http://www.cafepress.com/nutch">The
Nutch Store</a> are donated to The Nutch Organization.

<h3>By Check</h3>

<p>Donations by check may be sent to:</p>

<p style="margin-left: 40px;">
The Nutch Organization<br/>
PO Box 5633<br/>
Petaluma, CA 94955-5633<br/>
USA
</p>

<h3>By PayPal</h3>

<p>If you would like to make an easy cash donation you can send it to
our PayPal account:</p>

<center>
<form action="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr" method="post">
<input type="hidden" name="cmd" value="_xclick"/>
<input type="hidden" name="business"
       value="donate@nutch.org"/>
<input type="hidden" name="item_name" value="donation"/>
<input type="hidden" name="no_note" value="1"/>
<input type="hidden" name="currency_code" value="USD"/>
<input type="hidden" name="tax" value="0"/>
<input type="submit" value="Donate via PayPal" name="submit"/>
</form>
</center>

<h3>Equipment and Services</h3>

<p>Donations of equipment and services are also very much appreciated.</p>

<p>In particular, we need rack-mountable CPUs with 4GB (or more) of
RAM each.  We also need lots of 200GB (or larger) hard drives.  Note
that, in order to minimize our operational costs, we need to keep our
hardware base as uniform as possible, so we may be picky about what
hardware donations we'll accept.  Unless the donation is a large
number of identical devices, we'd rather have cash.</p>

<p>Currently our hosting is provided by the Internet Archive, so we do
not at present need donations of bandwidth or machine room space.</p>

<p>Please send inquiries to <a href="mailto:donate@nutch.org">donate@nutch.org</a>.</p>

</body>
</page>
