<page>

<title>developer policies</title>

<body>

<h3>Definitions</h3>
<ul>
  <li>code - all Nutch software and documentation.<br/>
  </li>
  <li>committer - a member of the small group who may directly make
changes to the code.</li>
  <li>contributor - someone who contributes code to Nutch indirectly
via a committer.</li>
  <li>developer - committers and contributors</li>
  <li>license - the license in <a href="../../LICENSE.txt">LICENSE.txt</a>.</li>
  <li>organization - the copyright owner of Nutch code.<br/>
  </li>
</ul>
<h3>Decision Process<br/>
</h3>
All Nutch decisions are made by a simple majority vote of all
committers.  Votes are made by email on the <a
 href="mailto:dev@nutch.org">dev@nutch.org</a>
mailing list.<br/>
<br/>
In general, Nutch operates by having just a handful of committers who
trust one another.  Thus most changes by committers may be made
unilaterally without explicit authorization.  <br/>
<br/>
In particular:<br/>
<ul>
  <li>The decision process itself may be changed by a simple majority
vote.</li>
  <li>Committers are added and removed by a simple majority vote of
existing committers.</li>
  <li>Disputes about code changes are resolved by a simple majority of
committers.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Change Process</h3>
Committers should always perform a clean recompilation against the
latest version of the sources.  Compilation should succedd without
warnings.  Javadoc should always build without warnings.   All
unit tests must complete successfuly before code is committed.<br/>
<br/>
In other words, the following steps must be performed prior to each cvs
commit:<br/>
<pre style="margin-left: 40px;">cvs update -d<br/>ant clean test javadoc<br/></pre>
We also have an automated nightly build process which
sends email to the developer list if any of these fail.<br/>
<h3>Contributions</h3>
Nutch welcomes contributions from non-committers.<br/>
<br/>
Contributions must:<br/>
<ul>
  <li>be submitted by email to the mailing list <a
 href="mailto:dev@nutch.org">dev@nutch.org</a>, or attached to a bug
 report</li>
  <li>be in patch-file format, as generated by 'cvs diff -Nu'</li>
  <li>conform to the coding conventions of the project.</li>
  <li>use the license.</li>
  <li>assign copyright to the organization.<br/>
  </li>
</ul>
<h3>Coding Conventions</h3>
Java code should conform to the contentions described in:<br/>
   <a
 href="http://java.sun.com/docs/codeconv/html/CodeConvTOC.doc.html">http://java.sun.com/docs/codeconv/html/CodeConvTOC.doc.html<br/>
</a><br/>
All Java code modules should be accompanied by <a
 href="http://www.junit.org/index.htm">JUnit</a> tests.<br/>
<br/>
Every public or protected class, method and field must have an
informative Javadoc comment.<br/>
<br/>
</body>
</page>
